







Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

Possess over 14 years of IT industry experience, which involved Configuration Management, Software Asset Management, Process Management, Knowledge Management, Incident Management, preparation of Run Books & User guides, On-line help, Technical documentation, Proposals, etc.,. Majority of my experience has been mainly in Infrastructure Maintenance projects that involved a high level of interactions with various Tracks and SMEs. I would like to explore opportunities in the below fields.

Software Asset and Configuration Management.

Infrastructure Service Delivery Management.

Building / Maintenance / Migration of Cloud Infrastructure & Applications.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Delivery Manager -IT Jan 2015 to Till Date

Roles & Responsibilities

Implemented CMDB Improvement plan to bring the current CMDB to match Industry Standards and Governance Process & Change Policies to keep the CMDB up-to-date. Implemented Industry best practices to build and maintain CMDB.

Defined the process of Software Asset Management to Track Software License of EUC Device Licenses to report the status for compliance and availability Tracking.

Implemented ITOM (Operations Management / Service Tracking) to Track the Impacted Service during outages and to plan Changes in the environment.

Automated the Change and CMDB Task workflow to make sure that all the required changes updated in CMDB with minimal manual intervention.

Planning and Implementation of Auto-Discovery and Relationship building between Cls in ServiceNow. Standardized the periodic Audit Process to make the Audit Process convenient to the Technical Team Members and visibility to the Management to identify the gap and perform post audit remediation plans.

Standardized the Weekly Report for Auto-Discovery Changes (Authorized / Unauthorized), CMDB CTASKs, and Changes requires CMDB Updates.

Conducted periodic trainings to the Technical / Management Team members to utilize the benefits of CMDB in the ITSM Tool.

HCL Technologies as Associate Project Manager Mar 2009 to Jan 2015

Clients: Multiple Clients (Shared Services)
Role: ITSMCross Functional Manager

Period : Nov 11 - Jan 15
Roles & Responsibilities:

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld Configuration Management: Responsible to Implement CMDB for multiple Shared Services Clients. Prepared Project Implementation Plan, Co-ordination with Customer and Technical Tracks, Data Discover & Validation, until UAT. Process and Audit: Implemented Documentation best practices, Documentation Process & Life cycle and Standardized the audit frequency and Audit Process.

Knowledge Management: Prepared the Project Plan & Process. End-to-End implementation of KM Module for multiple customers in Ticketing Tool. Conducted multiple demonstration sessions to the resources to use KM module effectively.

Standardization & Documentation: Standardized the Run Books and SOPs received from various teams in Shared Services. Prepared Run Books, SOPs, DR plan, and Process Diagrams for all teams in Shared Services. Document Management Systems: Manage and Maintaining the Shared Services Document Management systems (Site) & Server - Document Portal. By means of Design, Site Creation and Repository Management, Uploading, Version Control and elimination of duplicate documents.

User Access Management - Online Site & Shared Repository: Facilitates with access rights depends upon the User Level and requirements including ensure access rights to entire Shared Services Resources. Incident management: Handled the four member's team to drive and handle the Incident Process during major Incidents.

Covansys A CSC Company as Technical Writer

Apr 2008 to Feb 2009

Roles & Responsibilities:

Standardized the Technical documents for the PDOCS Standards (As per client's document standard).

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computer Science) from St. Xavier College, MS University in 2003

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (computer science and information technology) from anja college, sivakasi in 2005

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
ServiceNow		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.